

# YUVCICI JAVA DEVELOPER/ FULL STACK DEVELOPER

#### **PROFILE**

Java developer with 5 years of experience having Strong knowledge on J2EE, Spring and Spring boot to build Rest API's and having experience in working with databases in writing queries and stored procedures. Also crave to learn new technologies and have a working understanding of frontend frameworks such as React and Angular.

## **PERSONAL DETAILS**

## **Birth date**

22/03/1995

## **Nationality**

Indian

## CONTACT

- yuvaraj2295@gmail.com
- +91-8608275333
- https://linkedin.com/in/yuvarajq-a4869968/
- https://github.com/yuvaaraaja

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Technology Analyst

INFOSYS 2020 - Present

Designed and developed a set of micro-services using Spring Boot and Apache Camel as a replacement for web-services which was using legacy Integration platform (webMethods) and released it into production in cloud (AWS) thereby increasing the performance of the web service and implemented new features requested by the client (Bpost).

Working in an Agile team on user stories for adding new features in an full stack application that uses Angular for front end and Spring Boot for backend.

Associate

#### **COGNIZANT TECHNOLOGY SOLUTIONS**

2016 - 2020

Worked in the pilot team to reduce the interface related issues occurring in pilot applications in 3M and implementing enhancements requested by clients and on their major releases.

Worked as a developer and support analyst in IMES (Integrated Manufacturing Execution System)

– A Java enterprise application built using Servlet framework used for core manufacturing process across 3M plants.

Worked as a developer to add new functionalities in IMES API - A Java REST API built using Spring MVC and Hibernate which enables external applications to connect, access and process information from a centralized database dedicated for manufacturing process.

## **EDUCATION**

B. Tech (Information Technology)

SRI RAMAKRISHNA ENGINEERING COLLEGE

2012 - 2016

Higher Secondary Education (12th - Computer Science)

VIDYAAVIKAS MATRIC HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL

2010 - 2012

Secondary School Leaving Certificate (10th)

JAYCEE HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL

2009 - 2010

# **SKILLS**

100% C

Core Java, JDBC, Hibernate

50%

Spring MVC & Spring Boot

75%

PostgreSQL, MySQL, MS SQL Server

50%

JavaScript, React & Angular



Maven

50%

AWS (EC2, Load balancer, API gateway)



Docker and Kubernetes